It's you.
是你
The Korean who threw a bomb at Gyeongseong Station.
在京城站丟炸彈的朝鮮人
Which organization sent you?
哪個組織派你來的？
The commander is dead!
指揮官已經死了！
Damn it.
可惡
Geez.
天哪
This damn alarm. It's ringing even decades into the past.
這該死的鬧鐘，往前穿越幾十年還會響
Did you see that?
你有看到嗎？
Music played from that matchbox-looking thing.
那個火柴盒模樣的東西會播放音樂
-What is that thing? -Oh, my!
-那是什麼東西？ -天哪！
Answer me!
回答我！
I'm going to school.
我要去上學
The box just spoke.
那個盒子講話了
Is there someone inside the thing?
裡面是不是藏著人？
Are there any tasty restaurants around here?
這附近有沒有好吃的餐廳？
Geez. Forget it.
真是的，我不玩了
Don't move!
不許動！
I don't understand a word you're babbling.
你講的話，我一個字都聽不懂
I'm undereducated. I didn't even take the CSAT.
我沒有讀過書 連大學修學能力測驗都沒參加過
By the way, have you guys seen my stuff?
對了，你們有沒有看到我的東西？
It looks like a small rock, but it's very important to me.
像一塊小石頭，但是對我而言非常重要
I said don't move!
我叫你不要動！
Damn it.
可惡
You made a hole here.
這裡被你打出一個洞
I'm on a day trip, so this was my only outfit!
因為這是當天去當天回的任務 我只帶了這一套衣服！
-What the hell are you? -Speak in my language.
-祢究竟是什麼東西？ -講韓語
Who-- Who are you?
祢…祢是誰？
Me?
我？
I'm Joseon's nine-tailed fox.
我是朝鮮九尾狐
LEE YEON: A NINE-TAILED FOX WHO LOVED A HUMAN
（李硯：愛上一個人類的九尾狐）
FORMER GOD OF MT. BAEKDUDAEGAN
（白頭大幹山前山神）
LIKES: MINT CHOCOLATE ICE CREAM DISLIKES: DENTIST
（喜好：薄荷巧克力冰淇淋 厭惡：牙醫）
Shoot! Shoot and kill him!
開槍！槍斃祂！
Give me your gun.
把槍給我
I said give it to me!
我叫你把槍給我！
Stay still.
不要動
Don't even breathe.
連呼吸都憋住
Quit smoking, you punk!
戒煙吧，臭小子！
I'm his older brother. Smoking's bad for you, right?
我是祂哥哥，吸煙有害健康對不對？
Wait a minute.
等一下
Brother, you still alive?
哥哥，祢還活著嗎？
LEE RANG: HALF-FOX, HALF-HUMAN
（李朗：半狐半人）
LIKES: HIS BROTHER DISLIKES: HIS BROTHER
（喜好：哥哥，厭惡：哥哥）
DIED IN 2020 TO SAVE HIS BROTHER
（2020年為救哥哥而犧牲）
THIS GUY'S HALF-BROTHER
（這傢伙同父異母的弟弟）
-You called the Japanese Army on me? -Yeah.
-是祢叫日本兵來抓我的？ -嗯
"The Gyeongseong Station bomber is my brother."
“京城站的炸彈手是我哥哥”
Do I look like a bomber to you?
祢看我像是炸彈手嗎？
You're a walking bomb yourself.
祢本身就是行走的炸彈
Damn, it's annoying just to see your face.
天哪，看到祢的臉就好煩
So my brother's a scumbag even in the Japanese colonial period, huh?
即便在日帝殖民統治時代 我的弟弟依然是個人渣，是吧？
All thanks to my shitty upbringing.
誰叫我從小沒有教養呢
Are you baffled? I get it.
是不是很困惑？我理解
Because that's exactly how I feel right now.
因為我此刻的心情也是如此
Why am I back in the Japanese colonial era of Joseon,
我為什麼回到了朝鮮日治時期
filming some fake Western movie?
拍攝仿冒的西部影片？
Moreover, why has my deceased brother become a heavy smoker,
而且為什麼我死去的弟弟 變成了一個老煙鬼
roaming the Gyeongseong grounds?
在京城區域徘徊呢？
They say brotherhood is like a film noir.
他們說兄弟情就像是黑色電影
But there's a more complicated story behind why our family is such a mess.
但是我們家亂成這樣是有其複雜原因的
I'm a nine-tailed fox who fell in love with a human.
我是一隻愛上人類的九尾狐
And I paid a heavy price for that.
並為此付出了慘重的代價
You abandoned your duty as the mountain god
祢為了一個人類放棄山神的職責
and left the mountains for a human and--
離開山脈，還…
Yes.
對
I abandoned you.
是我拋棄了祢沒錯
For a long time,
很多年來
we were each others' foes.
我們始終是仇敵
-Did you miss me? -Want to die, brother?
-想我了嗎？ -弟弟，想死嗎？
After crossing the boundary between life and death…
一同出生入死後…
I've never abandoned you.
我從來沒有拋棄過祢
…we reconciled as brothers again.
…我們又變回了好兄弟
You better make it out alive.
祢最好活著出去
In 2020, I died once.
2020年，我死過一次
But I was reincarnated,
但我轉世了
fulfilling my lifelong wish to become human, but…
實現了做人的大願，但是…
I've been giving you a hard time for many years,
這些年來，我一直在折磨祢
but I won't apologize.
但我不會道歉的
But still, if we can…
話說回來，如果可以…
let's meet again.
和我重逢吧
My brother.
哥哥
My younger brother, Lee Rang,
我的弟弟李朗
sacrificed his life to save me and left my side forever.
為了救我犧牲自己，永遠地離開了我
4 MONTHS LATER
（四個月後）
Why can't Lee Rang reincarnate?
李朗為什麼不能轉世？
DISROBING OLD WOMAN OWNER OF THE STREAM OF THE DEAD
（奪衣婆，三途川守門人）
That's the law of the afterlife. It's the law!
那是來世的律法，律法就是這樣！
Man, that damn law!
這該死的律法！
EPISODE 1
（第 1 集）
He died to save me, you hear?
祂是為了救我而死的，知道嗎？
He may have saved you, but you know how many more he's killed, right?
祂是救了祢沒錯 但祢也知道祂有殺過多少人吧？
Fine.
好吧
I'll yield my custody rights, so bring him back.
我願意放棄監護權，幫祂轉世吧
Custody rights, my foot.
見鬼的監護權
Hey, you think I want to change the diapers of a 1,600-year-old man?
祢以為我想幫一千六百歲的人換尿布嗎？
I'll do whatever you say, old hag.
老妖婆，我願意任祢差遣
I see you've finally learned your place.
看來祢終於認清自己的身份了
Damn you.
可惡
Ever since my best performer retired, I've been having a hard time.
自從我的最佳業務員退休後 我一直過得很艱難
"On the condition that Lee Rang reincarnates,
“作為幫李朗轉世的條件
Lee Yeon will punish everyone that disturbs the living
李硯將懲罰所有禍亂陽間的妖物
and repay the kindness received."
並回報恩情”
-Sign it. -Hold on.
-簽字 -等一下
What's written here? Why is it so tiny?
這裡寫的是什麼？為什麼這麼小？
"Your term as a nine-tailed fox will last until the Disrobing Old Woman says so."
“祢身為九尾狐的期限 到奪衣婆主動解約為止”
An indefinite contract?
無限期契約？
Even insurance contracts are audited against such dubious clauses.
即便保險契約都不允許含有這類可疑條款
You-- You--
祢…
Old age hasn't affected your vision, huh?
祢不會是老眼昏花吧？
You can have me. Fine.
我可以賣身給祢
But I don't want immortality or indefinite contracts.
但我不要永生，也不要無限期契約
Let me die on the same day as Ji-ah.
請允許我和智雅死在同一天
That's my only condition.
這是我唯一的條件
They say a fox never abandons its mate until the day it dies.
據說狐狸至死不會拋棄伴侶
I see your love for her remains unchanged.
看來祢對她的愛依然如初
YOUR TERM AS A NINE-TAILED FOX WILL END ON YOUR WIFE'S DEATH
（祢身為九尾狐的期限 到祢的妻子死亡為止）
LEE YEON
（李硯）
It seemed as if this story would have a happy ending.
當時看來，這個故事似乎會有圓滿的結局
However…
但是…
AFTERLIFE IMMIGRATION OFFICE
（來世出入境管理事務所）
Was it because of the lunar eclipse?
是因為那次月食嗎？
Or…
還是因為
because of the uninvited guest who slipped in during the eclipse?
趁著月食溜進來的不速之客？
Since the disaster at the Stream of the Dead,
自從劃分陰陽兩界的三途川
the boundary between the living and the dead,
發生災難後
everything associated with me and my life began to go awry.
與我和我的生活相關的一切 都開始偏離軌道
Mint chocolate chip, right? Will that be to go?
薄荷巧克力口味是嗎？要外帶嗎？
For here. I'd like to order two today.
內用，今天我要點兩份
The other one's for your wife, huh?
另一份是買給你妻子的吧？
-Yeon! Yeon! -That scared me.
-阿硯！ -嚇我一跳
-We're in trouble! -What brings you here?
-我們有麻煩啦！ -祢怎麼來了？
My gosh-- Some guy wearing a red-white mask…
天哪，有一個頭戴紅白面具的人…
…came and stole the guardian stone!
…來盜走了守護石！
-What's that? -The precious stone on our roof.
-那是什麼東西？ -我們屋頂的寶石
The King of the Dead made it himself
那是閻羅王親手做的
to protect the boundary between the living and the dead.
用來保護陰陽兩界的分界線
If it's so special, why put it on the roof and not in a safe?
如此特別的寶貝為什麼放在屋頂上 而不裝進保險箱呢？
That's because it marks the boundary of the Stream of the Dead.
因為它標誌著三途川的邊界啊
The boundary?
邊界？
Then that means--
那表示…
Yes, evil spirits are flocking in!
沒錯，邪靈都要湧進來啦！
Goodness-- Hurry, let's go!
天哪，我們快走吧！
Honey, don't come. Yeah, yeah.
老婆，不要過來了，好的
I just need to find the guardian stone, right?
我只需要找到守護石，對不對？
Where did that thief run off to?
那個小偷逃到哪裡去了？
Of all places…
偏偏就是…
Here?
這裡？
This leads straight to hell, right?
這裡直通地獄吧？
Fiery-Cauldron Hell? Ice Hell?
火湯地獄？寒冰地獄？
It doesn't lead to hell…
不是通往地獄啦…
Been a while, Disrobing Old Woman!
好久不見，奪衣婆！
Gosh, you've been occupying the Stream of the Dead for too long!
天哪，祢霸佔三途川太久了吧！
What a crowd you've mustered.
一群烏合之眾
I was going to give you this when your term ended.
我本來要在祢的契約到期時送祢的
-A watch? -You will eventually go blind and deaf.
-手錶？ -祢會逐漸變得又聾又瞎
Can she not hear me?
祂聽不到我講話嗎？
Disrobing Old Woman!
奪衣婆！
When that happens, look into this watch. Don't forget you're on borrowed time.
到時候看看這塊手錶 記住，祢的時間不多，要好好利用
-Yes, sir. -Disrobing Old Woman--
-遵命 -奪衣婆…
-Good. -Attack!
-厲害 -進攻！
My goodness.
真是的
Go!
出發吧！
Find the stone and return before the Hour of the Tiger.
找到那塊寶石，在寅時之前趕回來
Hour of the Tiger… So just before sunrise: 5:00 a.m.
寅時…那就是早上五點日出之前
Oh, how do I come back?
對了，我怎樣回來？
Through the same cabinet.
一樣通過這個櫃子
Remember, the gate will close at the Hour of the Tiger.
記住，儀門將在寅時關閉
Where is he going?
祂要去哪裡？
Stop him!
攔住祂！
Go!
快走！
I'll be back.
我會回來的
Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人！
-Oh, gosh! -Shin-ju?
-天哪！ -申炷？
Where's Lord Lee Yeon?
李硯大人呢？
-Hurry! -Yes, ma'am.
-快點！ -是，夫人
Just a minute--
等一下…
It's so bright.
好曬喔
What's this? Where the hell…
搞什麼？這究竟是哪…
What the…
怎麼…
What?
什麼？
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
Wait…
等等…
-Shall we go to Mitsukoshi? -Okay.
-我們去三越百貨吧 -好的
My face powder has run out. What do you want to buy?
我的散粉用完了，妳想買什麼？
Extra! Extra!
號外！
Year 13 of the Showa era…
昭和十三年…
Year 1938?
1938年？
Japanese colonial period?
日治時期？
Damn, I don't believe this!
拜託，開什麼玩笑！
Oh, geez!
我的天！
D-16 HOURS
（“三途川時間儀門”）
UNTIL THE STREAM OF THE DEAD'S "GATE OF TIME" CLOSES
（將在十六小時後關閉）
Lord Lee Yeon?
李硯大人？
Water Snail Bride?
田螺姑娘？
What brings you here? You haven't been here in a while.
祢怎麼來了？祢很久沒來這裡了
Oh, I haven't?
是嗎？
Didn't you go to Gunsan with Shin-ju last year?
祢去年不是和申炷去了群山嗎？
-What in the world are you doing there? -Right.
-來這裡做什麼啊？ -沒錯
So I just got back from Gunsan…
我剛剛從群山回來…
It's not like I'm running a restaurant. I'm just running errands and such…
我又不需要經營餐廳 只是跑腿辦事而已嘛…
What time is it?
現在幾點了？
It's 1:10 p.m.
下午一點十分
Wow, that meticulous old hag. She even set the time difference.
老妖婆果然一絲不苟，連時差都設定好了
-Time difference? -Never mind.
-時差？ -沒事
For goodness' sake.
真是的
Someone over there--
那邊有個人…
That masked man is staring straight at us.
那個戴面具的人在直愣愣地盯著我們
Who are you?
祢是誰？
GYEONGSEONG STATION
（京城站）
Popsicles!
賣冰棒啦！
Pay before you eat! Damn, you brat.
先買再吃！臭小子
I'm sorry.
對不起
Thief! Thief!
小偷！
Move!
快點！
Who are you people?
你們是什麼人？
Protect the commander!
保護指揮官！
Freeze!
不許動！
Damn it.
可惡
What?
嗯？
Ki Yoo-ri?
奇宥莉？
Chiyorika? Chiyorika!
智代梨！
For Korea's independence!
為朝鮮獨立而戰！
Hooray!
萬歲！
Where's the bitch who threw the bomb? Find her!
丟炸彈的賤人哪裡去了？找到她！
For Korea's independence! Hooray! Hooray!
為朝鮮獨立而戰！萬歲！
Shit.
該死
Damn it!
可惡！
Hey.
喂
-Hey, hey! Hey, you! -Shoot 'em!
-喂，別跑！ -槍斃他們！
Long live Korea!
朝鮮萬歲！
Hooray!
萬歲！
Spy alert! Run!
間諜警報！快跑！
-Hide! Hide! -Get out of here! Run!
-躲起來！ -快走！快！
The horse!
扶我上馬！
One, two, on you go!
一、二，上！
What the heck?
搞什麼？
They're not human.
原來不是人類啊
Giddyap!
駕！
Stop, you punk!
站住，臭小子！
Don't come near! Giddyap!
不要過來！駕！
Boss!
老大！
How dare you touch my stuff?
祢竟敢碰我的東西？
Oh, boss…
老大…
-Rang. -Lee Yeon?
-阿朗 -李硯？
You're alive.
祢還活著
You're alive…
在這個時代…
Die!
去死吧！
Thank goodness.
謝天謝地
Your heart is beating, and you're breathing just fine.
心跳有力，呼吸正常
You're alive, my brother.
我的弟弟還活著
-I'm so glad. -Get lost, you bastard.
-太好啦 -滾開，混蛋
Did you take opium or what?
祢是不是抽鴉片了？
I'm sorry.
對不起
We don't have much time, Rang.
我們的時間不多了，阿朗
Hand it over.
交出來
Here.
在這裡
It's right here.
就在這裡
Oh, my-- Goodness!
我的天！
Oh, gosh. That was nauseating.
天哪，要吐了
Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人！
Why isn't anyone passing by?
為什麼沒有人經過？
How long have I been walking?
我已經走多久了？
Excuse me! Here! Over here!
不好意思！在這邊！
Stop, stop!
停車！
-Can I get a ride? -Get in.
-我可以搭車嗎？ -上車
Get in? Okay. Great!
上車？太好了！
KOO SHIN-JU - A NATIVE FOX LEE YEON'S RIGHT-HAND FOX
（具申炷：本土狐狸，李硯的得力助手）
SPECIALTY: ABILITY TO UNDERSTAND ANIMALS
（專長：理解動物的能力）
-What's up with your hair? -Don't touch me! I'll kill you.
-祢的髮型是怎麼回事？ -別碰我，不然我殺了祢
I can't believe you're a bandit leader.
祢居然是一個土匪頭目
You've been doing this for 30 years?
三十年來，祢一直在當土匪嗎？
Yeah. Stealing, plundering and killing.
沒錯，偷盜、搶劫和殺人
It's my fault.
都怪我不好
After I lost my beloved, I couldn't afford to care for you.
我失去摯愛後，沒有精力照顧祢
You… You know you disgust me, right?
祢知道我看到祢就噁心吧？
I know, but…
我知道，但…
I really wanted to tell you this.
我真的很想告訴祢一句話
I…
哥哥我…
did you wrong.
對不起祢
Let me go.
放我走
Can't you see that I'm trying to believe your bullshit?
看不出來我很想要相信祢的鬼話嗎？
You sure this is okay, boss?
老大，這樣真的沒事嗎？
He's family.
祂是我家人
Wow. No wonder. You sure are strong, sir.
難怪，祢真的太強悍了，先生
Get off me!
走開！
What are they? If not human, what?
既然祂們不是人，那是什麼東西？
-A pack of wolves. -I see.
-一群狼 -原來如此
We used to have a different boss,
我們以前有自己的首領
but Lord Lee Rang slit his throat in one go, so--
但祂被李朗大人 一下子割斷了喉嚨，所以…
-You turned coats? -But I prefer Boss Rang.
-祢們變節了？ -但我更喜歡朗老大
Is Rang good to you?
阿朗對祢們好嗎？
No.
不好
Even so, a whole bunch of guys are lined up to join our gang.
即便如此，還是有一堆人排隊 想要加入我們的幫派
Why?
為什麼？
Boss divides the stolen goods equally among us every time.
老大每次都讓我們平分贓物
-That's not easy, you know. -Cut the crap and get out.
-這可不容易 -少廢話，出去吧
Yes, sir.
是
Oh, stop that.
別嗅了
Let's go.
走吧
Have some.
喝吧
I'll just have one drink.
我只喝一杯
What is that thing, anyway?
對了，那是什麼東西？
Something that shouldn't be in this era. I must return it to its rightful place.
不該出現在這個時代的物品 我必須把它物歸原主
You have no idea
祢不知道
how much I longed to see you again
我有多麼期待再見到祢
and how much I missed you.
我有多麼想念祢
Drink.
喝吧
I had so much to tell you.
我有很多話要跟祢講
But now, just seeing you breathe makes me happy.
但是現在，看祢呼吸我都覺得開心
Say something.
講句話嘛
After today, you might not see me for a while.
今天過後 祢可能有段時間都不會再見到我
So say whatever you have in mind.
所以，有什麼心裡話就講出來吧
Let me hear your voice.
讓我聽聽祢的聲音
Hang on.
等一下
What's that in your mouth?
祢嘴裡是什麼？
You have something in your mouth.
祢嘴裡有東西
You bastard.
混蛋
Run, run, run!
快跑！
-Run, run! -Move it.
-快跑！ -讓開
Go! Get her!
快！抓住她！
Bring her.
帶她走
My beer…
我的啤酒…
My beer, you bastard! Give me back my beer! My beer!
我的啤酒，混蛋！還我啤酒！我的啤酒！
That hurts! It hurts!
好痛！
Watch out for fire.
小心著火
The fire, fire… Watch out for fire.
火…小心著火
What's this crazy prick saying?
這個瘋子在講什麼？
I said, "Watch out for fire."
我說的是：“小心著火”
Fire!
火啊！
It burns!
燙死啦！
You're awake.
醒啦
Who are you?
你是誰？
"Who are you"?
“你是誰”？
I'm the one you owe money to. You'll have to pay for my beer.
我是妳的債主，妳欠我一瓶啤酒
I don't have money right now, but I will pay you back.
我現在沒有錢，但我會還你的
I'm Sun-woo Eun-ho, a reporter for the Seonwoo Daily.
我是《鮮于日報》的記者鮮于恩好
If you're a reporter,
既然是記者
why are you being chased by armed detectives in broad daylight?
為何在光天化日之下 被一群拿槍的警探追捕呢？
You smell of gunpowder too.
而且身上還有火藥味
Then don't go saving women who reek of gunpowder.
那就不要救散發著火藥味的女人嘛
Can I have some?
給我喝一點？
Wait.
慢慢喝
Your name?
你叫什麼名字？
I should at least know who I'm indebted to.
我至少應該知道債主是誰吧
Mu-yeong. I'm Cheon Mu-yeong.
無影，我叫千無影
Are you a doctor?
你是醫生嗎？
You've treated my wounds like a professional.
你把我的傷口處理得很專業
Well, I was only trying my best.
我只是盡力而為罷了
So I can collect beer money from the injured.
這樣才能從傷者那裡討回啤酒錢
As a reporter, I've met my share of swindlers.
身為記者，我見過不少騙徒
But you're not one.
但你不是
Well, what am I, then?
那我是什麼？
You're either very kind
你要麼特別善良
or someone petty criminals like swindlers can never measure up to:
要麼是普通騙徒永遠無法企及的角色
someone lethal.
亡命之徒
What are you filming?
你們在拍什麼影片？
Are you guys film extras? I part-timed as one a couple times too.
你們都是臨時演員嗎？我也做過幾次兼職
But where's this truck headed?
但是這輛卡車要去哪裡？
-To a mine, of course. -A mine?
-當然是礦山了 -礦山？
We're definitely not headed there.
肯定不是去礦山
I haven't heard a word from anyone who left to earn money.
去那裡賺錢的人全都音訊全無
All gone without a single trace.
消失得無影無蹤
What happened to your forehead?
你的額頭怎麼了？
Oh, this? I was smacked for saying I wanted to go home.
這個嗎？我說我想回家，就被他們打了
Smacked?
打了？
They assaulted an extra? You should report them already!
他們居然毆打臨時演員？ 你該舉報他們的！
To the Human Rights Commission! Or just petition--
找人權委員會！或者請願…
Silence!
閉嘴！
Shit, my arms are numb!
該死，我的手臂都麻了！
What the…
搞什麼…
Geez, that bastard.
天哪，那個混蛋
Hold on.
等一下
Five o'clock? I slept for three hours?
五點鐘？我一覺睡了三小時？
This is the scene you all saw at the beginning.
這就是你們一開始看到的場景了
It's you.
是你
Fast forward!
快轉！
FAST FORWARD
（快轉）
You could have dodged it, right? Why didn't you?
你可以躲開的，對不對？為什麼不躲？
It was the only way you'd believe me.
只有這樣，祢才會相信我
About how sorry I am.
對祢究竟有多愧疚
Now that you've defeated me, let's call it even.
既然祢打贏了我，我們算是扯平了
So don't waste your precious time resenting me.
所以，不要再浪費寶貴的時間來恨我了
Quit being a bandit or whatever.
不要再當土匪了
Just find a bit of happiness, okay?
去尋找幸福好不好？
You speak as if you'll die soon.
這番話像是臨終遺言
-You can't die from this, right? -I'm not dying.
-這點傷要不了祢的命吧？ -我不會死的
But I have to go.
但我必須離開
Where to?
去哪裡？
Have a good life, you brat.
好好生活，傻瓜
Show me what you've got.
活出樣子來給哥哥看看
Hey, you evil bastard.
祢這個惡毒的傢伙
You say all you want is just to leave again?
滿口鬼話只為了再一次離開嗎？
Why did you show up pretending to be nice just to abandon me as you please?
為什麼要假惺惺地出現 又再一次隨心所欲地拋棄我？
Who says I'm abandoning you?
誰說我要拋棄祢了？
Rang!
阿朗！
You okay?
祢還好嗎？
You. Listen to me carefully.
祢給我聽好
Foxes always repay kindness and repay their enemy, no matter what!
狐狸向來有恩必報，有仇也必報！
No, Rang. Wake up.
不，阿朗，祢醒醒
Myoyeongak.
妙緣閣
Take me to Myoyeongak…
帶我去妙緣閣…
Rang-- Rang!
阿朗！
D-11 HOURS
（倒數計時十一小時）
Identification!
身份證！
Pass!
通過！
Aren't you that bitch from earlier?
妳不是之前那個賤人嗎？
You have the wrong person.
你抓錯人了
No one can fool me. Okay?
沒有人可以愚弄我，知道嗎？
My identification is legitimate.
我有正當的身份證
What's important isn't you.
妳是誰不重要
I'm Jung Dae-seung of Jongno.
我是鐘路的鄭大勝
Do you know who I am?
妳知道我是誰嗎？
Jung Dae-seung…
鄭大勝…
You hear how I deal with the likes of you?
妳有沒有聽說我如何對付你們這類人？
You cut every bodily tendon…
你會切掉全身的肌腱…
I even got a medal for my torture skills.
我的酷刑術可是獲過獎的
Please spare me.
求你饒命啊
It really wasn't me.
真的不是我做的
I swear on my dead parents you have a gunshot wound on your shoulder.
我拿我死去的雙親發誓 妳的肩頭一定有槍傷
You little shit!
死傢伙！
-Don't move! -No! No!
-不要動！ -不！
What the hell?
搞什麼？
Ryuhei Kato,
加藤龍平
government-general of Korea's chief commissioner.
政府派來的朝鮮首席專員
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
I was investigating a suspect in the bombing incident.
我在調查爆炸案的嫌疑人
And who is this person?
這個人是誰？
She says she's a reporter from the Seonwoo Daily.
她自稱是《鮮于日報》的記者
I'll find out who's pulling her strings.
我會查清她背後的主謀
This woman is Seonwoo Daily.
這個女人就是《鮮于日報》
-What? -Her father is the head of Seonwoo Daily.
-什麼？ -她的父親是《鮮于日報》的社長
Sho Tawara.
俵祥羽
Her mother is an aristocrat of the Japanese Empire.
她的母親是日本帝國的貴族
Sho Tawara?
俵祥羽？
Do you mean Seon Woo-chang, the richest man in Gyeongseong?
難道是京城首富鮮于佑昌？
That's his daughter, Ginko Tawara.
那是他的女兒俵銀子
She's also…
同時…
my sister-in-law.
她還是我的小姨子
My apologies, sir. I must've lost my mind.
對不起，我一定是發瘋了
-Please forgive me, miss. -Get up.
-請小姐原諒我 -起來
-Do you see the reason for my actions? -Of course I do.
-小姐可以理解我的做法嗎？ -當然可以
But that's too bad. I have a habit of repaying my debts.
但是很遺憾，我向來有債必還
Cut his tendon, please.
割掉他的肌腱，謝謝
The one on his right leg.
右腿
Goodbye, sir.
先生慢走
I've had a good time.
我吃得很盡興
MYOYEONGAK
（妙緣閣）
Where is it? Where do I go, damn it?
在哪裡？我該去哪裡？該死
Pardon me.
不好意思
Geez.
天哪
Cheers to a lovely night!
敬良宵！
Lovely!
好看！
I need to think.
我得想一想
Why did Rang want to come here?
阿朗為什麼想要來這裡？
Excuse me.
打擾了
-Should I call a doctor? -What is this place?
-要我叫醫生嗎？ -這是什麼地方？
It's Gyeongseong's finest restaurant, aside from Myongwolgwan.
除了明月館，這是京城最高檔的餐廳了
-Is that all? -Pardon?
-僅此而已？ -什麼？
Watch him for a second.
幫我照看祂一下
My goodness.
天哪
Hey.
喂
You were an old man a moment ago, right?
祢剛剛還是一個老人家吧？
Pardon me.
不好意思
It says "family."
上面寫的是“家人”
I can live longer if I sacrifice my daughter, right?
只要獻出女兒，我便能多活幾年對不對？
Father…
爸爸…
Is living a longer life
用自己的小孩
worth exchanging your child for?
換取長壽，值得嗎？
Take her away.
帶她走吧
So that…
看來…
is your choice.
你已經做出了選擇
Thank you, sir.
謝謝
Thank you!
謝謝！
Father! Father!
爸爸！
Father…
爸爸…
Don't cry. All that's severed are your worldly ties.
不要哭，他只是斬斷了妳的世俗羈絆
Now you will never have to cry again.
以後妳再也不需要哭了
Who are you?
祢是誰？
People call me this…
大家都稱我為…
Long-Living Dong Bang-sak.
三千甲子東方朔
Dong Bang-sak…
東方朔…
The one with the longest life span in Eastern tales?
東方傳說中最長壽的人？
So that's why Rang--
難怪阿朗…
Hey, I'm glad I ran into you. Let me borrow your life span.
很高興遇到祢，把祢的壽命借我吧
Why would someone who isn't a mortal desire my life span?
祢並非人類，要我的壽命做什麼？
My brother is dying.
我弟弟快要死了
You must know, sir, a deal with a demon comes with a price.
祢要知道，和魔鬼交易是有代價的
-That's why you made this rule? -You shouldn't covet life so easily.
-祢定下這條規矩就是為了這個嗎？ -生命不是可以隨便貪圖的
I usually make up the rules myself.
我往往都會自己制定規矩
-Save my brother, this instant. -Strike me.
-現在快點去救我弟弟 -動手吧
If you do, you can have my life span.
那樣的話，我的壽命就歸祢了
-What the hell is this? -I can't even die as I please.
-怎麼回事？ -我想死都不行
Who are you? And where's Lee Yeon?
妳是誰？李硯在哪裡？
Can't you hear me?
聽不到我講話嗎？
What?
什麼？
Am I dead?
我死了嗎？
Hey! Hey! Hey!
喂！
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
I have to find Lee Yeon.
我必須找到李硯
Lee Yeon.
李硯
Lee Yeon!
李硯！
Hey!
喂！
So you want me to draw a ball out of this box?
祢要我從這個盒子裡抽一個球？
If you bring me what you pick, I'll trade my life span for it.
如果祢能帶來祢抽中的東西 我便拿我的壽命交換它
-What are the choices? -Things worth someone's life:
-裡面有哪些選項？ -值得拿命交換的東西
money, fame, family, luck
金錢、名譽、家人、運氣
and Uturi's sword.
還有烏圖里的劍
Uturi?
烏圖里？
UTURI THE LEGENDARY BABY GENERAL
（烏圖里：傳說中的嬰孩將帥）
Why the baby general's sword?
為什麼要嬰孩將帥的劍？
Because it's the only thing that can cut me.
因為只有它可以砍傷我
Are you perhaps…
祢是不是…
trying to die?
很想死？
All I have left is loneliness.
我只剩下孤獨了
I've lived for thousands of years.
我已經活了數千年
Everything I cared about, and everyone who cared for me,
我曾經在意的一切和所有關心我的人
have vanished like dust.
都已經化為塵土
All right.
是啊
Let's do it.
抽籤吧
What will it be?
會是什麼呢？
How much longer will you take?
祢還要多久啊？
Shit!
該死！
Here.
給祢
UTURI'S SWORD
（烏圖里的劍）
-The sword of Uturi. -My goodness!
-烏圖里的劍 -天哪！
Hey, can't I trade it for something else?
我不能用別的東西交換嗎？
I know for certain it's in the worst place possible in this era.
我敢肯定 它絕對保存在這個時代最可怕的地方
If you don't want my life span, you may give up.
如果祢不想要我的壽命，可以放棄啊
Fine.
好吧
If I bring you the sword, you promise to save my brother?
如果我把劍帶來，祢一定會救我弟弟嗎？
Of course.
當然會
Fine. I'll go get it.
好吧，我去找
If by any chance
萬一
my brother dies before I return,
我弟弟在我回來之前死掉的話
I'll cut you up.
我就砍死祢
Hey, can't you hear me?
聽不到我講話嗎？
I'm here. I'm right behind you!
我在這裡，就在祢身後啊！
Geez.
真是的
Damn it.
該死
Oh, goodness…
天哪
-Hold on. -Yes.
-等一下 -沒錯
Do I have a sinus problem?
難道我患上了鼻竇炎？
Wow, you idiot.
天哪，傻瓜
Why, you…
為什麼…
You'd always fall sick as a kid too.
祢小時候也常常生病
Were you born just to torture me?
祢生來就是為了折磨我吧？
This bastard.
混蛋
That's what you say to your dying brother?
居然和奄奄一息的弟弟講這種話？
Please hang in there until I get back.
請祢撐著點，等我回來
I will…
我永遠都
never give up on you.
不會放棄祢的
What's this?
這是什麼？
D-9 HOURS 20 MINUTES
（倒數計時九小時二十分鐘）
Will I be able to save Rang in time?
我來得及救阿朗嗎？
GUNSAN
（群山）
The problem is this:
問題是
The creature wielding the sword of Uturi in this era
在這個時代揮舞烏圖里之劍的生物
happens to be me.
剛好是我
Ah-eum.
峨音
Where in the world are you?
妳究竟在哪裡？
Why can't you be reincarnated?
妳為什麼不能轉世啊？
What's wrong with him?
祂哪根筋有毛病？
Well, that's embarrassing.
好丟臉
Lord Lee Yeon! Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人！
Kneel before him! I found them, sir.
跪下！我找到祂們了
You raccoons in disguise.
祢們這些偽裝成人的浣熊
I know of your sins.
我知道祢們的罪行
-What do you mean, "sins?" -Your wife's name-- What is it?
-什麼罪行？ -祢妻子…叫什麼來著？
-I'm Bae Ah-eum. -Ah-eum.
-我叫白峨音 -峨音
Ah-eum!
峨音！
-Who said you could use that name? -Wait, wait-- Sir!
-誰准祢用這個名字的？ -等一下，大人！
It's Lord Lee Yeon's first love's name, who passed before her time!
那是李硯大人的初戀的名字 她年紀輕輕就去世了！
-How should we know that? -She'll change her name.
-我們怎麼會知道？ -祂會改名的
You've no need to altercate with Lord Lee Yeon!
沒必要和李硯大人惡意爭論！
What, you prick?
這混帳說什麼？
What'd you just say? Ah-eum-hate?
祢說什麼？“峨音真嫩”？
-Ah-eum-hate? -No, altercate. Altercate, sir!
-峨音真嫩？ -是“惡意爭論”啊，大人！
-Alter-- -Come here. Come here.
-惡… -過來
Hey, you!
喂！
What? Ah-eum-hate?
祢說什麼？峨音真嫩？
-How dare you? -Lord Lee Yeon, that's enough!
-好大的膽子 -李硯大人，夠了！
-Stop it. -Ah-eum-hate?
-別打了 -峨音真嫩？
-Just go, go. -What's wrong with him?
-快走吧 -祂怎麼回事？
-Ah-eum-hate, huh? -Sir, no!
-峨音真嫩？ -大人，別打了！
We all feel lost at times.
我們都有迷茫的時候
This is precisely one of my worst moments.
這正是我狀態最差的時期之一
What the hell? I'm all out.
搞什麼？鴉片沒有了
Lord Lee Yeon, please quit smoking opium. You're already addicted!
李硯大人，拜託祢不要抽鴉片了 祢已經上癮了！
Hey.
喂
If I don't do this…
如果我不這樣做
I can't stop crying.
會忍不住哭個不停
Okay, just get some sleep. I'll go find some more.
睡一覺吧，我去幫祢找鴉片
What's this?
這是什麼？
Was there always a mirror here?
這裡一直有一面鏡子嗎？
Man, why did Shin-ju put a mirror here?
真是的，申炷幹嘛要在這裡放鏡子啊？
Hey!
喂！
-Die, you opium addict! -I'm here to get revenge, you jerk!
-去死吧，大煙鬼！ -我是來報仇的，混蛋！
-Who the hell are you all? -You struck me with lightning!
-你們都是什麼人？ -祢用閃電劈過我！
How could you break my leg because my face displeases you?
祢怎麼能因為看我的臉不爽 就打斷了我的腿？
I'm truly sorry, okay?
我真的很抱歉，好嗎？
-I'm busy. Gotta go. -You're going nowhere!
-我很忙的，我得走了 -祢哪裡都不能去！
Hey, you!
祢這傢伙！
Hey, retreat, retreat!
撤退！
-You want another one, huh? -Just you wait and see.
-還想再來一次嗎？ -祢等著
Damn, how tiring. I should've lived a little more nicely.
可惡，累死了，我不該活得如此狼狽
Lord Lee Yeon?
李硯大人？
Shin-ju.
申炷
D-6 HOURS
（倒數計時六小時）
Why are you doing this?
為什麼要這樣做？
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
What do you think you're doing?
祢們在做什麼？
What if you'd choked her to death?
萬一掐死她怎麼辦？
You can't let my precious food vanish on me, can you?
總不能讓我寶貴的食物在我面前消失吧？
What?
什麼？
He wasn't sharing his life span.
祂不是在分享壽命
He was taking them.
是奪取壽命
I have to tell Lee Yeon.
我必須告訴李硯
Wait a minute…
等一下…
-Can you see me? -There you are.
-祢能看到我嗎？ -祢在這裡啊
He can't see me. He can hear me.
祂看不到我，但能聽到我講話
Darn. I lost him.
該死，被祂跑了
His body. Bring his body to me.
祂的身體呢，把祂的身體帶過來
Yes, sir.
遵命
You going somewhere?
祢要去什麼地方嗎？
I'm going for a walk-- or stroll.
我要去散步，隨便走走
-I'll escort you out. -No.
-我陪祢去 -不要
I should go by myself…
我要一個人去
to develop my independen--
鍛煉一下自理能力…
-You just go inside. Go inside. -What?
-祢先進去吧 -什麼？
Lord Lee Yeon, wake up! Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人，醒醒！李硯大人！
Don't you think the thunder on your tail is a bit much?
沒必要用尾巴引雷吧？
How dare you disguise yourself as me?
祢竟敢偽裝成我的模樣？
Besides, that's mine.
另外，那是我的東西
Well, yes. It is.
是啊，沒錯
Strictly speaking, what's yours is mine and--
嚴格來講，祢的就是我的…
Shut up.
閉嘴
No one has ever touched what's mine
凡是碰過我東西的人
and survived.
沒有一個活下來的
I know. Better than anyone.
我知道，我最清楚了
But I'm a little busy right now.
但我現在有點忙
-Damn it! Oh, that head. -That head.
-該死！這腦袋 -這腦袋
What? You shit!
什麼？混蛋！
Let this--
放開…
Oh, darn it!
該死！
Hey, you prick. This is called an arm bar.
混蛋，這叫手臂鎖
How's that? You didn't know, huh?
怎麼樣？祢不知道吧？
Hey, stop. You…
住手，祢…
You little prick!
小混帳！
Ah-eum.
峨音
Ah-eum was reborn.
峨音重生了
Where? Where is she?
哪裡？她在哪裡？
Oh, I think she's in…
應該是在…
Manchuria?
滿洲？
I'll find you, Ah-eum.
峨音，我會找到妳的
Ah-eum…
峨音…
I'm so sick of this.
真是受夠了
D-4 HOURS AND 50 MINUTES
（倒數計時四小時五十分鐘）
Will Rang be okay?
阿朗不會有事吧？
Please be okay.
千萬要好好的
What? Where did my body go?
什麼？我的身體去哪了？
Find him, no matter what.
無論如何都要找到祂
Is anyone there?
裡面有人嗎？
How may I help you?
有事嗎？
I'm looking for someone, and I've only one room left to search.
我在找一個人 現在只剩一個房間沒有搜過了
These are gisaengs' quarters. Please leave.
這是妓生的閨房，請離開
That's too bad, because I must search this room.
真遺憾，這個房間我搜定了
Are you sure?
確定嗎？
Even if I say I'll call Madam?
不怕我告訴閣長嗎？
Scour the place. I'm certain he…
仔細搜查這個地方，我相信
is here at Myoyeongak.
祂就在妙緣閣
Why is my body here?
我的身體為什麼在這裡？
Are you sure we can do this?
我們真的可以這樣做嗎？
It's a customer's request. And Madam gave us permission.
這是一位客人的要求，閣長也有准許的
If I'm not back by midnight, can you move my brother to a different room?
如果我午夜之前還沒回來 幫我弟弟換個房間可以嗎？
May I ask why?
可以告訴我原因嗎？
I have a hard time trusting others.
我這個人很難相信別人
You ruthless bastard.
祢這個無情的混蛋
I knew it.
果然不出我所料
D-1 HOUR
（倒數計時一小時）
-Did anything happen? -Yes!
-有出什麼事嗎？ -有啊！
Nothing happened…
完全…
at all.
沒有
-Tell him the truth! -Thanks.
-跟祂講實話！ -謝謝
No! Don't fall for it!
不！不要上當！
What do I do? What…
怎麼辦？怎麼…
Damn it!
該死！
You can see me, huh?
妳能看到我？
Really? You can see me?
真的嗎？妳能看到我？
Mister, are you a ghost?
叔叔是鬼魂嗎？
-How come only you see me? -My grandma is a shaman.
-為什麼只有妳能看到我？ -我的祖母是巫師
THE PRESENT
（現在）
-Is Yeon back? -Not yet.
-阿硯回來了嗎？ -還沒有
Time's almost up.
時間快到了
Where in the world is that punk?
那個臭小子跑哪裡去了？
Hurry.
快點吧
You must hurry, Yeon.
阿硯，祢必須快一點
Open the door!
開門！
Damn it!
該死！
-Where's the sword? -Here.
-劍呢？ -給祢
-We have a deal. -Wait.
-我們有過約定的 -等一下
-You cheated, right? -What do you mean?
-祢作弊了吧？ -什麼意思？
This raffle box.
這個抽籤盒
-You messed with it. -Not a chance.
-被祢動過手腳 -不可能
There were a total of 44 marbles in there.
裡面一共有四十四顆珠子
But every single one had "Uturi's sword" written on it.
但是每一顆上面都寫著“烏圖里之劍”
Do I look like a fool?
祢看我像個傻瓜嗎？
If you knew, why did you get the sword?
既然祢早就知道，為什麼還去尋劍呢？
Same reason as you.
理由和祢一樣
Because it's the only thing that can kill me?
因為只有它能殺死我嗎？
You lied about wanting to die, right?
祢說祢想死是騙人的吧？
You wanted to destroy this sword.
祢想毀掉這把劍
I've been living forever off of humans' life spans.
我一直靠人類的壽命無限期地活在這世上
What of those you made younger?
那些被祢恢復青春的人是怎麼回事？
It's a simple trick. They age back in three days.
那只是簡單的小把戲 他們三天後便會恢復原樣
But by then, I won't be here.
但是到時候，我已經不在這裡了
You brat.
混帳東西
-But still, you can't kill me. -Why not?
-但是話說回來，祢不能殺我 -為什麼？
Because your brother is my hostage.
因為祢弟弟是我的人質啊
What do I do?
怎麼辦？
25 MINUTES LEFT
（倒數計時二十五分鐘）
I don't have time.
沒時間了
If I don't kill him now and jump into the cabinet…
如果我不能立刻殺死祂，跳進櫃子裡…
All right. Let's see who dies first.
好啊，那就看看誰先死
Oh, shit.
該死
What went wrong?
哪裡不對？
I've lived longer than you for a reason.
我活得比祢久是有原因的
He's one of the Ten Longevity Symbols: a leatherback turtle!
祂是十長生之一，棱皮龜！
Don't be ridiculous.
少來啦
You think I don't know they're working with him?
妳以為我不知道你們都是一夥的嗎？
I'm Lee Rang. I borrowed this body.
我是李朗，這具身體是我借來的
Stop that nonsense!
不要胡說八道！
How can I tell him that my soul borrowed this girl's body?
我要如何要祂知道 是我的靈魂借住在這個女孩的身體裡面？
There's no salvation for those who don't try to save themselves.
不想自救的人不配得到救贖
Whether you live as a human or a fox, it's your choice.
想做人還是做狐狸，祢自己選
But remember one thing, kid:
但是小朋友，要記住一點
There's no salvation for those who don't try to save themselves.
不想自救的人不配得到救贖
Turtle, turtle.
龜啊龜
Give me your head.
腦袋伸出來
If you don't, I'll roast you and eat you up.
不然我把祢烤來吃掉
Turtle, turtle.
龜啊龜
Give me your head. If you don't, I'll roast and eat you up.
腦袋伸出來，不然我把祢烤來吃掉
Give me your head.
腦袋伸出來
If you don't, I'll roast you and eat you up.
不然我把祢烤來吃掉
Turtle, turtle. Give me your head.
龜啊龜，腦袋伸出來
Kill him!
殺了祂！
-Oh, goodness! -My gosh!
-天哪！ -哎呦！
-Oh, my shoulder. -My legs!
-我的肩膀 -我的腿！
-Oh, my, my. -Oh, gosh.
-天哪
THE GATE OF TIME HAS CLOSED
（時間儀門已關閉）
Remember, it's by the Hour of the Tiger. Return before the door closes.
記住，截止時間是寅時 務必趕在關門前回來
Ji-ah must be waiting.
智雅一定在等我
Dong Bang-sak is dead?
東方朔死了？
What a shame. He was quite the money-maker.
真可惜，祂可是一棵搖錢樹
-Let's do this later. -Yes, ma'am.
-晚一點再打扮吧 -是
By the way, is Lee Yeon still handsome?
對了，李硯還是那麼帥氣逼人嗎？
I've spent hundreds of years chasing after him.
我追過祂幾百年
You get what I'm saying?
明白我的意思嗎？
I understand, ma'am.
明白
Then…
那麼…
bring me the largest and prettiest one.
把最大最漂亮的拿給我
We haven't seen each other in a long time.
我們很多年沒有見過了
Someone has locked me in the past.
有人把我困在了過去
However, they know nothing.
但是他們什麼都不知道
In an era without a woman to protect,
在一個沒有女人要保護的時代
the nine-tailed fox is far more ruthless than they'd expect.
九尾狐比他們想像中殘忍得多
It's time to hunt.
該狩獵了
Long time no see, fox.
好久不見，狐狸
What exactly is your relationship with that crazy woman?
祢和那個瘋女人究竟是什麼關係？
You, be mine.
祢，做我的人吧
I'll make him mine, even if I have to kill and taxidermy him.
我要得到祂 即使要殺掉祂做成動物標本也可以
Only beautiful women are targeted.
遭到襲擊的只有美女
Once we solve this case, we can catch the guy who stabbed you.
只要偵破這件案子 我們就可以抓住刺傷祢的人
Will you seek revenge?
祢要復仇嗎？
I'm not sure. Should I help Lee Yeon or him?
不知道，我該幫李硯還是幫祂呢？
Who are we?
我們是什麼？
A fox always pays his debts.
有債必還的狐狸